Reece Carruthers

Student at Northumbria University studying a BSc (Hons) in Computer Science

Email: carruthersreece4@gmail.com

Location: Newcastle Upon Tyne

<u>Personal Profile</u>

I am currently a third-year student studying Computer Science at Northumbria University, while I am working part-time as a software engineer at HM Revenue & Customs. I would describe myself as a person with a strong work ethic who takes pride in their work and has strong critical thinking skills, which helps me to solve problems. I would also consider myself to be a happy and approachable individual who is easy-going, but serious when the time calls for it.

I have always had a passion for learning and understanding Computer Science which has only grown over the past three years since starting University. I am particularly interested in the software engineering aspect of Computer Science.

Skills Summary

- Problem-solving
- Critical thinking
- Java, Scala and Play
- Test Driven Development
- Design and analysis skills
- Programming skills
- Strong communicator
- Customer service skills
- Leadership qualities

- Quick learner
- Collaborative working skills
- Time management skills
- Adaptability
- MongoDB
- Git
- Debugging
- Unit testing

Employment History

2022-2023 (Present) Software Engineer HM Revenue & Customs

Skills: Scala programming, test driven development, MongoDB, Json, HTML, CSS, HATEOAS & Restful API, WCAG, accessibility, GitHub, agile with scrum, collaboration, working under pressure.

Main duties performed:

- Worked as part of an agile with scrum development team to create the new computerised transit system (NCTS) which allows traders to declare their departure and arrival of goods going to and from common transit convention countries.
- Developed webpages using Scala and Play framework utilising test driven development.
- Innovated by creating Tampermonkey scripts, written in JavaScript, to help speed up manual testing of the service which worked by automatically filling out the form data of each page. The were written to be as maintainable and re-usable as possible.
- Worked under pressure to ensure development is on track for the legislative deadline for NCTS.
- Helped create HATEOAS & Restful APIs for the retrieval and submission of data.
- Developed new HTML components which met HMRCs strict accessibility requirements.
- Upskilled new members of the team.

2019-2022 Crew Member McDonalds

Skills: Customer service skills, collaborative working skills, communication skills.

Main duties performed:

- Talking to customers and taking orders has helped improve my communication skills.

 Working as a team in a fast-paced environment to batch cook food and to assemble food products such as burgers in a timely fashion has helped to improve my time management skills and collaborative working skills.

Education and Qualifications

2019-2024 BSc (Hons) Computer Science Northumbria University

Grade achieved: Predicted a 1st.

Skills:

- Led and managed group projects, I took responsibility for delegating tasks, organising meetings, and helping those in my group. This has further developed my leadership qualities along with my collaborative working skills.
- Improved programming skills and problem-solving skills by solving programming problems involved in university assignments and during non-working hours.
- Gained proficiency in many skills such as: object orientated programming in Java, MySQL, JavaScript, PHP, HTML5 and CSS.
- Gained leadership and time management skills by managing a team of students by fairly allocating tasks, setting deadlines, resolving conflict, and assisting where required.
- Design and analysis skills in a software engineering context have vastly improved by completing the following modules: systems analysis, program design and development, human computer interaction and software engineering practice.

Relevant Modules:

- Programming 1
- Programming 2
- Relational databases
- Program design and development
- Software engineering practice
- Systems analysis

- Web programming
- Web technologies
- Human computer interaction
- Computing fundamentals
- Code wrangling for beginners
- Introduction to information systems

2017-2019 A Levels Kenton School

Results: Computer Science: C Biology: C Chemistry: E

2015-2017 GCSEs Kenton School

Results: Achieved 10 GCSEs including Maths and English